Did you know that
the thumbnail is probably
one of the most
important parts of your
video? Now that might
seem crazy because it's
just a still image,
but if we can't
win the click, we
can't get people to
watch the video. We
can't get people into
our system. So this
is one of the
most important parts of
YouTube, working out how
to design thumbnails that
get a click. So
before we go into
strategies and design, I'm
just going to run
you through the basics
of what makes a
powerful thumbnail. And really
there's just three parts
to it. Context, curiosity,
and clarity. So let's
look at context to
start. So what is
context? Well, this is
probably the best example
I can give you.
Tell me what that
video is about.
You can't, right? Because
it just says, don't
do this. It could
be about recruitment. It
could be about playing
with fire, right? However,
if I whack a
YouTube logo on it
and then point it
at something from the
YouTube dash, you suddenly
know, ah, this is
about YouTube before you
read the title. So
context is about making
the topic clear in
a split second. And
it also then sets
up our viewers' expectations
and it will get
our buyers attention. Because
have you ever taken
a car for a
test drive before? What
happens after you've taken
a car for a
test drive is when
you're driving home in
your normal car, you
see the car you've
test driven everywhere. This
is known as frequency
bias. So when we're
interested in something, it
actually sticks out to
us more. So context
can actually harness frequency
bias if we put
things in a different
way. So if we
put things in a
different way, we can
actually harness in our
images that our viewers
are interested in. And
it doesn't have to
be like really over
the top. So let
me give you a
few examples of how
to give context in
an image. So we've
got Mark Tilbury here
and he's using money.
So that's one way.
We know that this
video is about making
money somehow. Vanessa Lau
has put the Instagram
icon in there. And
then the Google calendar
gives context to the
topic. So icons are
one way to give
context to a topic
of a video. And
you'll see in my
videos, I have to
use this little YouTube
logo all the time
because if I don't,
well, just having nothing
else works gives no
context. The next way
you can give context
is with familiar scenes.
So we can see
this here from Mark.
It's got the LinkedIn
dash and the LinkedIn
icon. So we know
this is going to
be about LinkedIn. Same
here. We've got the
Google ads dash. Here
in the background, we've
got a living room.
So this to me
instantly gives context to
design. And then this
one, we've got the
dumbbell. So the first
thing we're going to
do is we're going
to go to the
living room. And we're
going to go to
the living room. And
we're going to go
to the living room.
So we can see
here that this is
an icon. And we
can see that the
familiar scene gives context
as to the topic.
Another way to give
context is with text.
So Nisha just says,
look poor. So we
know this is going
to be about money.
This one has AI
design is insane in
it. So we know
it's going to be
about AI design. And
then this one's about
avoiding banks. We know
it's going to be
about banking. And then
items as well. So
James Smith here is
holding some sort of
thing. We don't know
what it is. We
can see a syringe.
We assume it's about
drugs and losing weight
in a split second.
So that gives context.
Well, if the expat
holds up a passport,
so he knows me
about passports. Deya holds
up a book, so
we know it's going
to be about a
book. The little test
you can run when
you make your thumbnail
is when you made
it, you look at
it and you go,
would my buyer instantly
understand the topic of
this video just by
looking at the image?
If the answer is
no, we might need
to add one of
those things to it
to give context. The
next part of the
triangle is curiosity. So
curiosity hooks viewers, very
powerful. And what we
want is our thumbnails
to make viewers think
how, what, or why.
So I absolutely love
this thumbnail. 22 million
views, simplest thumbnail ever,
just says this is
not yellow. So you're
going, well, what is
it then? This one
here, 7 million views,
because it's saying don't
eat. It's like, well,
hang on a second,
I've eaten salami loads
of times, why shouldn't
I eat that? It
makes me wonder how,
what, or why. Same
here, Dan Martell, act
like you're broke. How,
what, or why? And
we've got some more
examples here. So you
don't need subscribers. Well,
you've been told you
do. So you're going,
how do I do
this? How, what, or
why? Stop reacting. And
then 7 % forever
makes you wonder, how
do I get that?
There's money in there
to give context. We
know it's about making
money before we even
read the title. So
a curiosity test you
can run every time
you make a thumbnail
title is you ask,
does this make my
buyers think how, what,
or why? And then
we move on to
clarity. So what's clarity?
Well, clarity makes an
image really easy to
understand so that the
context and the curiosity
can actually work. And
to create clarity, what
I like to do
is use what I've
got. I call it
a hero. So the
hero is the thing
in the image that
needs to stick out
so that our viewers
go how, what, or
why, and it gives
context. So we can
see in this image
here, right? The hero
of the image to
me is this text.
It sticks out first.
Then it's Chris. The
hero in the image
is this text. Then
it's me. The hero
in this image is
this text, right? And
if we'd noticed Chris's
face first, it wouldn't
have been as powerful.
The item could also
be the hero. So
we can see here,
this thing's being held
up. Or you could
argue that the syringe
is the hero. It's
getting our attention. The
passport here is the
hero. It sticks out
first. The book here
is the hero. It
sticks out first. And
then you can have
things like the result
as the hero. So
this big graph spike,
and then this big
number, that's the thing
that's sticking out to
me. Then we've got
7 % forever. That's
a big result that
sticks out. And then
we've got these nice
big muscular arms and
shoulders. They're sticking out
a ton. So that's
the hero, right? Nice
and clear. So a
test that you can
run every time you
make a thumbnail. But
to make sure your
image has clarity is
just asking yourself, does
the most important element
to my viewers, it's
going to hook them,
get them interested, stick
out. So that's kind
of the very basics
of what makes an
amazing thumbnail image and
packaging to get a
click. Next, we're going
to move on to
some thumbnail strategies that
go a little bit
deeper.